Ah
Yao ( Chinese monster )
Kindest Yao
The baskets are full of pancakes
Take them all
Just spare my life
Hand over everything
That's it?
Business hasn't been great lately
Hardly makes a profit
Nice clothes you got there
Uh
Not taking them off?
Listen well
From now on
bring some good food and drink over
If you dare forget
Ah
You'll end up like this
What's going on?
Making a racket in the middle of the day
Who are you?
Who even are you?
Hold up
Who are you?
Me
King's Cave
No. 9527
So you're with King's Cave
My bad
Who do you run with?
I um
I run solo
Freelancer
Got some nerve robbing people on our turf
Won't do it again
I'm warning you all
The whole of Lang Lang Mountain
belongs to King's Cave
Got it?
Got it
Big Crow
This guy's my buddy
Can you let him slide this time?
Oh
You work in the kitchen?
That's me
I'm only doing this for Toadie's sake
( King's Cave )
I've tried for three years
Always get cut in the first round
If I don't make it in this year
I'll have to go back home
Ah
Your skills are fine
You just don't have the connections
This time it's different
My uncle just got promoted to
deputy chief of washing
Do a good job today
He can put in a good word for you
with Master Bear
Maybe that's your in
For real?
As long as this pot is real clean
This rag's useless
There's way too much grease
That's how Master Bear wants it cleaned
Nothing we can do
Watch this
Heh
Your bristles are pretty handy
Isn't it usually one pot?
Why are we cleaning four today?
You didn't hear
The King called a meeting this morning
The Tang Monk and his disciples are coming
The pots are for stewing them
The Tang Monk
Who's the Tang Monk?
They say his flesh is special
One bite and you'll live forever
Live forever
Keep it down
Say
If I do well
Can I get a piece of Tang Monk's meat?
Keep dreaming
That's for the kings
Master Bear's up there
And even he can't get a drop
Hey
All this scrubbing doesn't seem to be working
Your bristles are shot
No biggie
I've got more on my head
These are harder
You've always been a hard head
Make way for the King
This one looks barely touched
Take him away
Forty lashes
My King
Mercy
Still this much grease
Strip him of his scales
Tch
Show-off
Where's my calligraphy?
Calligraphy?
Where is my grandfather's calligraphy?
And my great-grandfather's calligraphy?
Get rid of these two
Mercy please
This hard?
Run
After them
Here
Hurry
Get in
No way
There's no way we'll fit
What are you waiting for?
After them
Coming
Where are we going?
What is this place?
My little hideout
What now?
What are we gonna do now?
If your uncle puts in a good word for us
do we still have a shot?
My uncle
He can barely save his own skin right now
My uncle even said
After the Kings are done eating the monk
He'd save me a little leftover meat
Now it's all ruined
Let's go
Go where?
Let's get out of Lang Lang Mountain
I had a decent job
And now it's all gone
It's all your fault
Give me back my King's Cave job
Give me back my immortality
Fine
Let's go catch the Tang Monk ourselves
What do you mean?
Isn't he still on the road?
Let's get to him first
Beat the King to it
You're kidding
I'm serious
First-come, first-served
What?
You're mad
The King will hunt us down
Isn't he already hunting us down?
It's all or nothing
Maybe we'll get to be immortal first
When the Tang Monk passes Holly's Hollow
You think the Yaos there might strike before us?
That's why we need to hurry
Move it
Did you see that?
I did
He's out of line
What are you doing?
Whoa
There are more of you Yaos
What's the world come to?
Under broad daylight too
How are Yaos being bullied by humans now?
Don't you lay a hand on me
I'm not scared of you
Where's your dignity as a Yao?
I was starving
So I came in looking for food
And he caught me
You are pathetic
Who do you run with?
Holly's Hollow
With a crew like that and you're scared?
You're embarrassing your king
My king's dead
When?
Today
Every Yao in Holly's Hollow got wiped out
I'm the only one who made it out
Who did it?
Sun Wukong
Who's Sun Wukong?
You don't know who Sun Wukong is?
Are you even a Yao?
Shut up
No one asked you
Stay out of this
Get back here
I just want to live
Then you talk
Sun Wukong is the Tang Monk's disciple
How are a few monks that strong?
Just monks?
Sun Wukong
On their journey to the West
they've wiped out gods knows how many Yaos
Taking you out
That would be a piece of cake
Scared now?
The four of them are in the capital now
feasting for ten days straight
Somehow you roaches are still around
I'm not scared of you
One hit and the village knows
Sun Wukong will show up in seconds
You believe me
Where's my gong?
Boss
Chill
We're not local Yaos
We're just passing through
Nope
Where's my hammer?
Boss
Don't be like that
No need for all this
No need
Don't mind him at all
Boss
Let's talk this out
We're leaving right now
Okay?
Toad
Where's your dignity?
Boss
That Tang Monk and his disciples
why are they going West anyway?
To fetch the scriptures and become Buddhas
That puts them on a whole new level
Think about it
Why would a powerful Yao like Sun Wukong
follow the Tang Monk around like that?
Sun Wukong's a Yao too
Yep
He's just a monkey Yao
Zhu Bajie's a pig Yao
Even their horse is a Yao
Then
Then why do they want to be Buddhas so bad?
Once you become a Buddha
everyone has to look up to you
Would you be immortal?
That's the least of it
Are we working or talking?
I'm ringing the gong
Okay okay
Run
No slacking
Faster
I'm keeping these two spears
If I catch you around here again
I'll give you a beating
It's over
We are completely screwed this time
Not necessarily
Catching the Tang Monk
Haha
A toad dreaming of eating the Monk's flesh
I'm so stupid
So naive
sob
Don't touch me
You run solo
You don't care
I can't go back now
I won't see my uncle again
You ruined my whole life
Aren't you full of big ideas?
Why don't you go fetch the scriptures?
Why don't you go and take down the King?
Go on
Say something
Say it
Good idea
Huh
Fetching the scriptures is a good idea
Are you nuts?
Joining the Tang Monk
We can pretend to be them
and go fetch the scriptures
Look
They've got a pig
I could be the pig
You play the Tang Monk
Then we find two more
Form a team and go together
What do you think?
You are crazy
Then we get to the West before they do
Grab the scriptures and become Buddhas
Become immortal
I'm telling you
I'd rather turn myself in
and get tossed off a cliff by Master Bear
than do this with you
I'm going back
Back to scrubbing my pot
First it's eat the Monk
Now it's be the Monk
like I'm buying any of that
Aren't you gonna stop me?
Aren't you worried I'll die back there?
Let me ask you
Even if we do go and fetch the scriptures
what if the Tang Monk catches up?
Didn't that villager say?
They're feasting for ten days
They are staying put for ten days
We'll leave as soon as the team is ready
I'm trusting you for one last time
Just so we're clear
I'm only doing this because you begged me
Drink some water
Mind your own business
( Hard Work Pays Off )
Is this Tang Monk a guy or a girl?
A guy
And?
He's a monk
Any idea what he looks like?
No idea
Ah
Then how am I supposed to make a portrait?
You're the artist
You figure it out
No wonder nobody hires you
When was the last time you even had customers?
You should be thanking us for showing up at all
Sun Wukong's a monkey
Zhu Bajie's a pig Yao
There's one more disciple
What's his name again?
That guy didn't say
Just go with your gut
Wait
At least you need
Done
Went with my gut
Take it or leave it
Something feels off
Mm-hmm
These four
They don't give off a scripture-seeker vibe
You know
What is a "scripture-seeker vibe"?
You're the artist
You tell me
Do another one
There's just
You know
Not enough presence here
The Tang Monk's head is too small
Bigger head Bigger presence
Shallow
This job
is impossible
I always meet the highest demands
with full commitment and no complaints
I'm done
That's all I've got
That's it
That's the one
As long as you two are happy
Looks like him
Really does
Where do we find Sun Wukong?
And what's-his-name?
Just take the sketch and go look
Hey
Stop right there
Huh Wha
It's been three days
And we haven't found anyone
The Tang Monk's leaving in seven days
What even is this portrait anyway?
Forget the monkey
There are no monkeys on Lang Lang Mountain
I've never seen one in my life
How do you still have an appetite?
I'm losing my mind over here
Wretched creatures
How dare you steal my offerings?
Great immortal Mercy
Please spare us
You eat my offerings
You get them back
Go get me two roasted chickens
Five-spice flavor
Yes
Right away
And tell the villagers
Bring more meat in the offerings next time
Braised
Steamed
I love meat
Pretending to be an immortal are we?
I'm not
My nickname is "Immortal"
Wait a second
Are you sure becoming a Buddha
beats being an immortal?
Of course
You're just hustling for some offerings here
Coming with us
We're talking serious future here
True immortality
You get it?
Give me a second
Let's go
Eager much?
I heard you were looking for a monkey
Yeah
Will an ape do?
He's the only ape on Lang Lang Mountain
But he is super introverted
No one knows about him
I only found him by accident
while digging a hole
He said that
ten years ago
he lost his whole family to King's Cave
He's the only one left
He cries every time he thinks about his mom
Do you guys miss your moms?
I do
But I don't even remember her face
I was always a bit sickly as a kid
You know why?
I was born premature
My ex said I talk too much
That's why she left me
Hey
Do you guys think I talk too much?
This is the place
Come on out
Remember me?
Immortal the Weasel
He's super shy
These two are good friends of mine
They mean no harm
Come on out
We've got some good news
Stop hiding
Come out
Come out now
We don't have any more
We're going West to fetch the scriptures
And we're inviting you to join us
Why are you running?
Don't be scared
Fetching the scriptures leads to Buddhahood
True immortality
sure beats hiding here forever
Are there gonna be
L-lots of people?
Of course
Excited?
No
You've got to take that first step
The outside world is full of color
You'll run into all sorts of fun stuff
And hey
You might even get a girlfriend
Ah
( No. 9981 )
You are from King's Cave
Yeah
What's wrong with him?
King's Cave wiped out his whole family
Don't be scared
He's not here to hurt you
He's not with them anymore
He got fired
Calm down
Listen to me
Come with us
It's your only way out
Don't worry
I've got an ultimate move
Boosts your power a hundredfold
Even if the Yaos from King's Cave catch up
we have nothing to fear
Look at this poor horse you stole
It's limping
It'll have to do
We're out of time
If we don't hurry
the Tang Monk will catch up
I can't hold it anymore
I think I'm going to puke
This horse's useless
Is it a ride or a pet?
Please
Stop crying already
What time do you guys usually go to bed?
I haven't been sleeping too well lately
I keep waking up at night
And when I do I can't fall back asleep
Let me give you guys some advice
Don't drink water before bed
How far have we gone?
50 kilometers or so
You tired?
Yeah
I meant-are you tired of talking yet
Oh
Not at all
There's a village up ahead
Let's go rob some food
Yes
I've been eating nothing but wild berries
I miss the taste of meat
I want roast chicken
What are you guys doing?
We're not Yaos right now
We're scripture seekers
No robbing
Then how do we eat?
Hey
I've got an idea
Let's beg
heh heh
I'm good at it
But you have to keep your mouth shut later
Let the Tang Monk do the talking
No problem
No talking
I just won't talk
No problem
Yeah
No problem at all
Not talking is easy
If I untie you now
would you behave?
Mm-hmm
Kind soul
We are seeking alms
Yeah
Which basically means
We want some food
Yaos
Should we
cover our faces?
Who's this?
Kind soul
We are seeking
Robbers
No
Catch the robbers
Young master
That drumstick of yours
Could you
spare some?
Who are you guys?
We are
from the Eastern kingdom of Tang
and going West to fetch the scriptures
The Tang Monk
Finally
Finally someone recognizes us
There are still sharp eyes in this world
Hahaha
That big head won't make you the Tang Monk
Trying to fool a kid?
Hahaha
Drop the act
We can't even fool a kid
What's the point?
You must be the Sha Monk
Sha Monk
I finally know my name
You look nothing like him
Sha Monk has a big beard
How would you know?
The town storyteller said so
Hey
Tell us more
You guys don't even have weapons
Sun Wukong's got a golden staff
Zhu Bajie carries a rake
Sha Monk carries a spade
And uses it to carry the luggage
What
I have to carry stuff on an empty stomach
That's not fair
Also
You talk too much
Sha Monk only has two lines
Which two?
Elder Brother ( Sun Wukong )
Master has been captured by Yaos
And?
Elder Brother
Master and Second Brother ( Zhu Bajie )
have been captured by Yaos
I don't wanna be the Sha Monk anymore
And you
Sun Wukong never cries
You are the hero
You are the coolest
The Great Sage
You are the one kicking all the Yaos' butts
Jojo
Dinner time
Coming
Wait
One more thing
Monks can't eat meat
I never could pass the test
to get into King's Cave
Had no strings to pull either
And now the king wants me gone
Finally
I got four people together
And I'm making something of myself
Turns out it's way harder than I thought
Is this just how my life's gonna be?
I told you this isn't going to work
See
We can't even fool a kid
I refuse to believe
we can't even beg for food
Look at us now
What's the point?
I'm afraid we'll starve to death
before we make it work
What are you doing?
I'm hungry
It's just a snack
No meat
Meeting you is the worst thing
that's ever happened to me
Alright
Enough complaining
Practice now if we still want the scriptures
Come
Come over here
Say
I am the Monkey King
You are the Mon-
Monkey King
You are the Monkey King
You are the Monkey K-
Say the line
The line is "I am the Monkey King"
I...I
I am not the Monkey K-
King
You are
Right now you are
Don't scare him
He's already so shy
And you
From now on
You only get two lines
Understood
I'll explode
Out of the four of us
you talk so much
You feel like a main character
You have to understand
You're supposed to be a side kick
A side kick
only gets two lines
That's not a side kick
That's kicking me to the side
Do you wanna fetch the scriptures or not?
Do you wanna be immortal or not?
I
Not talking
That's not living for me
Forget immortality
And you
Go find a way to fix that big head of yours
It's so late
Where am I supposed to find anything?
Are you going or not?
These people
Second Brother
Elder Brother's gone
What is he trying to pull?
Don't make me use my ultimate move
Why do you keep running away?
Don't you want to fetch the scriptures?
Hey
I feel like we could swap
He doesn't like to talk
he'd be perfect as the Sha Monk
I could be Sun Wukong
I can talk
You are just as good as anyone else
Be confident
Even that bumpy toad
can be the Tang Monk
You're the biggest among the four of us
and the handsomest
You're way better than him
Let's take it slow
Repeat after me
I am
The Monkey King
The M-
Mingkey Kong
Close
But not quite the right order
Monkey King
M-
Monking Key
Elder Brother
Master's been captured
Master and Second Brother have been captured
Hey
Who is this?
Where'd you get that beard?
I yanked some hair off of Elder Brother
Where are the other two?
Over there
How's it going?
I am Kong
Kongking
I'll show you conking
What are you doing?
Don't stop me
I'm gonna end him
Your teaching style is not working
You've got to be patient
You do it then
How hard can it be?
Just teaching a few words
Where'd you get that outfit?
Pulled it off a scarecrow
And these?
Got them by the field
So you stole them
I left plenty of firewood for the farmer
Hmm
You're getting it
Come on
Master will teach you
Hmm
You still need some luggage
Here
Pick these up
This-this is just bullying
Shh
Only two lines
But
Young Brother
Take this whetstone
If you feel upset
just sharpen your spade
Mon
M-on mon
Key
K-ey key
Monkey monkey monkey
Alright alright
Let me go
Just take a breath
Let me at him
Calm down
Chill out
Breathe
I'm hungry
Stop with the tongue
Alright alright
Let's go beg for some food
and give Elder Brother some more time
If we still can't get any food
we'll starve to death
All set
Ahem
Let's go
Uh-huh
Elder
We come from the East
and are going West for scriptures
We're out of food
So we have come to beg for some alms
Could it be
Master Xuanzang?
Xuecang?
Um
This is our Master
The Tang Monk
So it really is Tang Xuanzang
Oh
Yes
Please come inside
When was the last time you ate, Master?
You look positively green
Um
Why are you crying, Master?
I was always cooking for the King
This is the first time someone cooked for me
Master
If you want
I'll cook for you from now on
Master
Your have some lovely disciples
Huh
Master
Where are your disciples?
Amitabha
With war everywhere
Buddhism fading
Yaos roaming the land
They all ran off
Only I stayed here
watching this temple
Amitabha
That's why we are fetching the scriptures
to revive Buddhism
Hmm
If I were twenty years younger
I would gladly join your journey
Hm
Master-where is your kasaya?
Ah
Oh right
Where's my kasaya?
Master
Don't you remember?
The kasaya was stolen by Yaos
Ah right
My memory is not what it was
I still have a kasaya
Take it as my gift
Really?
I couldn't possibly
I'm old
And my days are numbered
Keeping it does me no good
Giving it to you can fulfill its purpose
If this kasaya reaches Buddha in my place
I will be honored through it
I wish you all a safe journey
May you find the scriptures you seek
Thanks for the food
Until we meet again
Travel safe
Thank you
When we meet Buddha
we'll put in a good word for you
and get this old temple fixed up
We did it
We really did it
The old monk called us scripture seekers
If this isn't the Tang Monk
then who is?
Allow me to say one thing
We are-
On the right path
We really are on the right path
Second Brother
Master's been captured
So diligent
Still practicing
Second Brother
Master
He really has been captured by Yaos
Very good
Keep it up
Ma-
Master is gone
What are you doing?
Let me go
Help
Is the water boiling yet?
Almost
My kings
We're out of star anise and green onions
Go fetch some
No need
Just boil him plain
Big brother
Why the rush?
The Tang Monk's meat grants immortality
So many powerful monsters ahead of us
failed to get a bite
You know why?
Why?
They took too long
They caught him but didn't eat him right away
Just kept fussing around
It wasn't like they didn't know
how powerful Sun Wukong is
But they waited
and got wiped out
Oh
Sun Wukong's that strong
What do you think?
Holly's Hollow and King's Cave
have been wiped out completely
Oh no
My uncle
Even though we are weaker than the other Yaos
We can be faster
Pot up, fire on
Start cooking
Blitz-feast
Alright
Enough talk
No explaining
Just boil him
I'm not the Tang Monk
I'm a fake
Let me go
A trick
You're pulling tricks on me
Huh?
I'm just a Toad Yao
Look
Is this how you stalled those other Yaos?
I'm not falling for it
Why won't you believe me?
At least wash me first before you boil me
Once you see me naked
you'll understand
Wash?
No time to wash
We don't care
Wait
Big brother
Boiling him with his clothes on
Isn't that kind of gross?
Hmm
Strip him
Quickly
See?
Purebred Toad Yao
These bumps
Full of poison
Big brother
Looks like he really isn't the Tang Monk
Hahahahaha!
No wonder none of the other Yaos
managed to eat you
You've got some serious tricks
Why are you so stubborn?
Illusion
Must be that monkey's doing
Isn't it?
Boil him
Aah
( Dog's Den )
Let's just admit we're fakes
and see if they will release Master
No way
If words get out that we're fakes
How will we continue our journey?
But we can't beat them
Why are you talking again?
Two lines only
Come closer
You're very important today
Got it?
Draw their attention
The Sha Monk and I
will rescue Master
I've got some moves
I can handle a few small Yaos
Practice with me again
I am the Monkey King
I am the Monk-eat
King
Chiefs
Three Yaos outside
One claims to be
The Monk-eat King
That fast?
He's not cooked yet?
Um Chief
The water's still warm
Hey
This is nice
Warm water's more comfortable anyway
Ugh
We missed our chance
A sip of soup is better than nothing
Everyone assemble
Ready
Go
Welcome
Warmest welcome
Honored guests from afar
Forgive us for the rough welcome
Greetings
Um what is this?
The hand-shaking salute
It's a local tradition
Shows our utmost respect for our guests
Where's my master?
Inside
This way please
The place is a bit messy
Hope you don't mind
My big brother is inside
ready to welcome you
Ah
Here you are
Huh
We saw you four holy monks
napping in the woods earlier
Didn't want to disturb you
Your master looked weary from travels
We couldn't bear to see him like that
So we warmed up some mountain springs
for him to bathe in
Reverend Master
How are you feeling now?
Stop scrubbing the same spot
My warts are starting to fall off
Oh
My disciples
Would you like to join?
The water is at a nice temperature
Master
We're panicking
like ants on a hot pan over here
How are you in the mood for a bath?
Nice outfits you've got
Ah
I see
I got you
Farewell
Warmest farewell
Guess the Monkey King isn't too chatty
Yeah
The strong and silent type
I'm jealous
Jealous of what?
Look at him
Didn't need to say a word
And all those Yaos
were terrified like whipped puppies
I want to swap
Swap what?
I want to be Sun Wukong
Quit it
We totally look alike
Look at the two of us
Same pouty lips
Hey
Elder Brother
You walk in the front
Yeah
Look ahead
Chest out
Head high
Carry the staff on your shoulder
Big strides
Swing your arms
No
Wrong arm
( North Zhang Village )
Why is there no one here?
We're from the Eastern Kingdom of Tang
going west to fetch the scriptures
We are passing through
and humbly seek alms
The village chief is here
He's here
They don't match the storyteller's description
Storyteller
Here
These four don't match what you said about
the Tang Monk and his disciples
I've never seen them myself
Just going off what I heard
See this?
This is the real deal
Take a good look
Get it right for next time
Got it
Masters
Since this Rat Yao came
Our village hasn't known peace
He steals from every house
We can't hold onto anything at home
Please, masters
Help us rid of this menace
Ha
That's nothing
Easy
Leave it to us
Thank you so much
I'll send some young men to assist you
No need
Just a rat Yao
we'll be done in seconds
Wow
Wonderful
Hey
Why are you agreeing to everything?
Do the math
The Tang Monk isn't far away
If we don't hurry
they'll catch up to us
Hey
This won't take long
Can we win the fight though?
No need for a fight
Just drop the Elder Brother's name
and he'll back down
He's right inside
You all stay back
We'll handle it
You finally showed up
The villagers asked us
to catch
you
Surrender now
Just you nobodies
Nobodies?
Don't you know who we are?
Who are you?
Take a good look
Recognize this guy?
Still nothing?
Go on
Elder Brother
Introduce yourself
I am the M-
Monkey King
Who's that?
Never heard of him
See?
I told you not to come
He doesn't even recognize us
You don't even know about the Monkey King
He's been around for 5000 years
In terms of seniority
Calling him grandpa would be an insult
He's like the ancestor's ancestor's ancestor
Enough yapping
Either fight
or get out
I'm a local Yao born and raised right here
In this life
I've feared no one
except for weasels
Ah
Stupid monk
What are you smirking at?
Let's all attack together
Doors are locked
You can't run now
Now
Do something
I've never been in a fight before
This guy
He's too fast
You city Yaos
All bark
No bite
You
Don't you have an ultimate move?
Use it
That ultimate move
You only get to use it
Once in your life
What are you waiting for?
Waiting for this rat to end you?
Did you just call me a rat?
I trained for over fifty years
Just so that
no one ever calls me that again
Aah
Aaaaah
Hit him
Now
Aaaaaah
Pow
Bam bam bam bam
Take this
You
How dare
Ah
Enough
already
The watermelons are freshly picked
Take them for the road
These are some white buns I just steamed
Take them
No It's okay
Masters
I spent all night sewing these soles
You guys have a long journey ahead
Take them
Please
Hurry up
These are thank-you banners from the villagers
Take them all
Wow
No need
You are all too kind
Just take them
We insist
It's too much for us to carry
Don't you have a pole?
You masters are all so powerful
What's a little more stuff?
I
I-I-wait
Masters
Let me ask one more thing of you
My daughter lives in Hillside Village 100 km out
Their villagers recently lost some kids to Yaos
If you pass by
could you please help
These Yaos are outrageous
Don't worry
We'll get those kids back
( The King of Dogs )
Every time
I read these writings left by the holy monks
I feel at peace
Reporting
My kings
There are four monks outside
One of them claims to be the Monkey King
Oh
Is that so?
Little Brother
I will head outside to check
Alright
I-I'll be there in a bit
Humph
Gather round
Who dares trespass
on my sacred grounds?
Heh heh heh
I'm your Grandpa Sun
Hahaha
Take a look at yourself
With your scruffy look
you dare pretend to be the Tang Monk?
Pretend?
I haven't had human flesh in a while
I'm going to feast today
Boys
Take down these imposters
I will fight you till the end
Hi-yah
Argh
( Left to Hardstone Hills )
( Right to Tantan Village )
We're almost at your place
It's been three years
I haven't been back once
Let's drop by then
Not in a rush anymore?
We made good time
We can spare a day or so
and drop off this food at your parents'
Travel light
No more
Mom
You forgot me
I'm still hungry
Eating too much will make you sick
Who are you guys?
Mom
Come try this
What is it?
It's a veggie bun
Tastes really good
Yum
Save some for mom
Where'd you get all this?
Villagers gave them to us
Don't lie to me
We are Yaos after all
Mom
We're kind of a big deal now
Both Yaos and humans treat us with respect
What exactly are you doing?
Fetching
the scriptures
Listen up everyone
My big boy is back
They love him down in King's Cave
Compared to your sons
He's way more promising
Hey
Mom mom
Stop yelling
That's my boy
Auntie
Calm down
Toadie
We have you to thank for this
Three years ago
I sent him to you and your uncle for help
It's all thanks to you that he got in
I can finally
relax now
Oh
By the way
How's your uncle?
My uncle
What happened to him?
It's a long story
Is your gourd empty again?
No no no
See?
It's full
This full
That means you didn't drink a sip
What's the point of carrying it around?
Okay okay, I'll drink some
That water must be stale
Let me refill it for you
Having
Having a home is nice
These past few days
must have been tough for you
Today at my place
you can talk as much as you want
No need to sharpen that spade
You can start talking now
Ok
You must be pretty busy at King's Cave
Yea yea
The King keeps giving us loads of work
So I never really had time to visit
I understand
When you're just starting out
The boss always works you hard
Just do your best
Don't let your mind wander
You barely drank any
Drink more
Don't be like your dad
Quitting a perfectly good job
Just to practice the mystic arts
Now he's completely lost it
Speaking of
Where's dad?
Out back resting
Dad
I came to see you
These are my friends
Hello uncle
Sun Wukong
The Tang Monk
And you
Zhu Bajie
Don't let mom hear about this
I didn't tell her
Tell me about it
Don't be mad
We quit King's Cave
Doing our own thing now
Dressed as the Tang Monk's bunch
Going west to fetch the scriptures
Nicely done
What?
Is he trying to move around again?
Ah
It's nothing
Auntie
He's just happy to see his boy
Let me keep you company
Come
Son
Get the wine for me
It's right there under that rock
Dad
How'd you get that in there?
I put it there back when I could walk
Haven't had a sip all these years
Don't listen to your mom
You'll never amount to anything
If you stay at King's Cave
Fetching the scriptures is a good idea
With the scriptures
You can become a Buddha
Nobody will dare look down upon you
Remember the big move dad taught you before
How well do you know it now?
Oh I'm still working on it
Then don't use it until you absolutely have to
A single use will turn you
back into a normal animal
Back in my day
When I learned this move
I decided to run solo
I was one surge of Qi away from mastering it
But I thought I couldn't do it
and gave up
That's how I ended up like this
I hope that you can carry on what I started
Otherwise you'll spend your whole life
living with regret
Don't worry dad
When I fetch the scriptures
I'll come back for our family
And we'll live happily ever after
Yea
You four take care of each other out there
Eat well
Drink plenty
Don't you worry
Auntie
We'll take care of ourselves
Those two friends of yours
don't seem to like to talk
That Ape Yao is doing way better today
He used to never smile
and was nervous all the time
That other kid's nice too
Carrying that heavy load all by himself
Not much of a talker either
Sharpening his spade now and then
A good kid
He's not talking as much
Hey
Get your uncle another sip of wine
Auntie
You sure don't look your age
Really?
Not a single wrinkle
Aw
Aren't you sweet?
Really
I'm just being honest
I believe you
You are a good kid
Uncle's going to teach you a move
Come
Come close
That Yao
His moves were no joke
Knocking them both on the ground
in the blink of an eye
Got that?
That's one powerful move
I've never told anyone
except for you
Then there's your Brother Ape
With thunderous force
He smashed the fake immortal right into the wall
I always thought
your brother was the strongest of us
But now I know
Brother Ape was hiding his strength all along
Heh heh
That move brother Ape does
I've got a name for it
"Crashing Mountain and Roaring Sea"
That smash was unbelievable
It knocked the fake immortal
back to its animal form
You need to finish this gourd
Before noon time each day
At least four gourds a day
You guys make sure he drinks it
In the load
I packed some dried sweet potatoes
Very tasty
You guys share
Make sure you have some yourself
Don't let them eat all of it
Just wait for our good news
Mom
Don't scold Dad so much
Got it
Don't worry
( North Zhang Village )
The Tang Monk's group just passed through, right?
Did they head that way?
Mmhm
Hey
There's a band of fakes coming
posing as the Tang Monk's bunch
Should be here tomorrow
Watch out
Hey
The Tang Monk's group should be close by now
Push through
Full speed ahead
Yea
Bajie
What does it say?
On that temple there
Too far
I can't tell
Little
Um
Little Thunderclap Temple
Great
Let's beg for some food there
My king
Four monks are approaching from afar
Looks like the Tang Monk's group
What?
Already?
So it really is them
My king
Should we hurry and eat the kids now?
No time
Tell the underlings
Change and get ready
Bajie
Why do all these monks
look so mean?
Not all of them
That one looks alright
That chubby monk got a kind face
May I ask
Are you the Tang Monk and his disciples?
Ah yes
So Master
You know me
Insolent
In the presence of the Buddha
You must bow in reverence
Buddha
Uh
Excuse us
We'll step outside for a bit
Did he say Buddha just now?
They seriously don't
recognize us?
Did something
give us away?
We've already reached the West
Guess so
That was really the Buddha
We didn't recognize him earlier
Will that be a problem?
Looks like we're fine
All is quiet
That can't be
We've been practicing for half a year
We don't have much of a tell
How about this?
We act right away
and take them down
What do we do then?
Go ask him for the scriptures
Then we get out of here
I
Hold your horses
We might not be
Sun Wukong's match right now
I will eat the children later today
That's when we act
This is the moment
Don't mess this up
Keep it together everyone
It all comes down to this
My ignorant self was blind to greatness
The Tang Monk and disciples
Greetings to your holiness
The Tang Monk
By my estimates
You should be arriving tomorrow
How come you arrived today?
Amitabha
We traveled day and night
Eager to fetch the scriptures
We may have been a bit too fast
You must be tired from the journey
Go and rest for a while
No need for rest
We are in a hurry to return to Chang'an
Might we receive the scriptures now?
No rush
Hey Master
Look
After fetching the scriptures
Even Yaos can be Buddhas
Buddha
To be quite honest
All my disciples wish to become Buddhas
Can we do that by reading the scriptures?
Of course
A hundred Reads
and you're a Buddha
Please grant us the scriptures Buddha
Dhritarashtra
Virudhaka
Here
Go prepare the scriptures in the back
Yes
My king
Where are the scriptures?
King
No nonsense
Go to prepare them
Oh
These two
Very naughty
Ahahaha
Hahahaha
Oh
Yes speak
Buddha what kinds of scriptures
are you giving us?
Let me first hear
what scriptures
you now recite in the East
What scriptures?
Quick quick
Speak up
You are the greatest Monk in the East
Can't remember the name of you scriptures?
Of course I can
It's called
The Legitimate Scriptures
Your holiness might not have heard it
We live far away after all
Insolent
Of all the scriptures in the world
There is nothing the Buddha does not know
I've long heard of these eight scriptures
Said to be beautifully written
You can hardly unhear them
I don't believe we got that
I want to hear the Tang Monk
Recite these scriptures
Shall we?
My master has been feeling under the weather
and has a sore throat
The Buddha wants to hear a recitation
And you are still making excuses?
Mumbo-jumbo
Do re mi fa
She picks seashells
Peter Piper picked a peck
Allow me to explain
My master invented this unique way of chanting
Using the language of the East
Great sounds need not be uttered
As if it is the murmur of an infant
The humming of summer insects at noon
The sound of flower petals
Wilting and falling to the ground
Simultaneously the roar of an emperor
And the whisper of a commoner
Sometimes reciting forwards
Sometimes reciting backwards
Like the starry sky above us
Chanting his own resolve
Striving to turn the Legitimate Scriptures
in to an artful performance
Blurring reality and fantasy
What say you dear Buddha
about this performance?
The Tang Monk's recitation
has a clear tenor
a balanced baritone
and a rich bass
Closing my eyes
I see the undeniable beauty
of the Eastren Lands of Tang
Its lovely mountains and Rivers
I see a prosperous nation
and a content people
Only a true master can recite
the Legitim Eight Scriptures
In such a dramatic fashion
so passionate through and through
Truly the greatest monk
of all time
Alright
It is now noontime
Have some food from the temple first
Get some rest
No need to worry
We can wait right here
You all must be tired
It's alright
We aren't tired
Why are you all so stubborn?
We've got food and wine all ready for you
Not even one bite before you go?
There's wine
Great
I haven't had a sip in ages
That's more like it
May I say something?
Monks
Must not drink wine
Who are you?
Enough pretending
Underlings
Reveal yourselves
This is your "golden staff"?
Looks like a back scratcher
Are you joking?
My king
Look
A filthy toad
That's an illusion
More like delusion
You bunch of imposters
How dare you insult us scripture-seekers?
I'll report you to the real Buddha himself
Have you no shame?
We saw through your cover
Why are we letting them live my king?
These Yaos are so powerful
Nothing like the ones we faced before
Wukong has no staff now
What do we do?
Don't worry
Let's find a new one in the village up ahead
We'll find a way
Are you
the Tang Monk and his disciples?
Children
Come on out
Sun Wukong is here
Elders
A few days ago
my father sent word by pigeon
Telling us that you are coming
The whole village's been waiting day and night
You are finally here
Your father
The Village Chief of North Zhang
So this is Hillside Village
Right
Your father said the kids were taken by Yaos
Aren't they all here?
Five kids have been taken
We didn't know what to do
So we hid the rest of these children
We've long since heard of your powers
Please show mercy masters
Save our children
No need for kneeling
Don't worry
I promised the Village Chief
We'll bring the kids back safe and sound
Oh bless you honorable Masters
Our saviors
Tell us
Where is the Yao?
Behind the mountain
In Little Thunderclap Temple
I told you
There had to be more children
Here they are
Catch them
Run Molly
Master
Yao
You will not touch a hair on her head
Out of my way
No stay away
Crashing Mountain and Roaring Sea
Great Sage
That wasn't bad
Ah
Wukong
The Sha Monk
Reporting for duty
We caught five children this time
Plus the five we caught before
We have ten in total
That'll do
Master
You put on a good show
Come
You are coming back with us
The king wants to see you
You
are working together
No
We are scripture-seekers
Scripture-seekers
With those pathetic skills
you think you can complete the journey?
Don't step on him, boss man
Please spare him
Tell these people
who you really are
We are pretending to be the Tang Monk
Now you know what you are?
Take a good look everyone
These are just mutts and strays
Tell your friends and relatives
Neighbours near and far
If you ever see these four fakes again
Beat them to a pulp
You
Drag them back with me
My children
I didn't mean to lie
Your father really asked me to help
Liar
You are still pretending
Keep acting you lot
Shame on you
Count yourselves lucky
Those four heavenly guardians couldn't act
The king liked your acting
He's letting you stay as the Four Guardians
Costumes are in the back
Go change and start rehearsing
No
I want to
go fetch the scriptures
What don't you get?
All those villagers know we are fakes now
The news will spread like wildfire
How are we supposed to continue?
You guys never had a shot to begin with
You know why?
The Buddha and Sun Wukong
They go way back
Sun Wukong wreaked havoc in heaven
five hundred years ago
That's when he met the Buddha
Zhu Bajie and the Sha Monk
are both reincarnations of deities
The Tang Monk is the Golden Cicada
Close friend of the Emperor's
You think anyone a scripture seeker?
Like you four nobodies?
You'd better stay here
and fix those brains of yours
Stick with the king
That's your best shot
I
I'm not going to be part of your evil schemes
Ungrateful fools
Do you know how many Yaos want a job here?
And can't find a way in?
Apart from Lion Camel Ridge
No one dares compare with
Little Thunderclap Temple
Even century-old Yaos
would gladly scrub pots
Just to work here
And here you are being picky
Go get changed and start rehearsing
The king will come take a look in a bit
If I'm being honest
This is way better than King's Cave
Wha
What about the children?
Great Sage
You must help me
There are four Yaos pretending to be you
They even got my brother
How did you find us?
I asked around heading west
Then I saw your horse outside the temple
So I knew you had to be here
Please Great Sage
Help me avenge my brother
We are fakes
Those four are the real deal
You are joking
Really
We are fakes
How is that possible?
You four Masters have a righteous look
And there's a light in your eyes
Those four sketchy-looking fakes
cannot hope to compare with you
Open up those puppy dog eyes of yours
and take a good look
I am an ugly wild boar
He's not the Tang Monk
He's a toad
who has done nothing except complain
Look at him
Even the beard made from the Ape's fur
Fake
Illusions
Now look at him
Shy and timid
Stuttering all the time
All this time
he can't even say
"the Monkey King"
I don't buy it
You are trying to fool me again
But they are going to eat children
If we just sit here and watch
Are we really scripture-seekers?
See?
You are not a scripture-seeker
You are a Yao
What do those kids have to do with you?
Yaos eat humans
That's the way it's always been
We should still try to save the kids
I'll ask the king later
Maybe there's a shot
Keep pretending
I almost believe you
My king
I put those four here
So they can practice by themselves
Take a look
Why aren't you changed yet?
The Tang Monk is arriving tomorrow
If anything goes wrong
Do you know what will happen?
Who are you?
I get it now
You're trying to catch those four too
My king
This Yao followed us here
He keeps messing with our rehearsal
No wonder you guys are pretending still
I get it
Hey
The one with the yellow eyebrows
Let's go catch those four together
Come
Follow me
Let's prepare together
Oh
Okay
You can't fool me
You are the real scripture-seekers
When we catch them
Let me finish off that fake monkey myself
and avenge my brother
My king
If we promise to play the Four Guardians
Can you let the children go?
Bargaining with the king
Do you want to die?
You lot
want a bite of the Tang Monk's flesh?
Are we worth it?
The four guardians
should at least get a pair of kidneys
This is definitely better than King's Cave
I need to eat the children
to boost my power
Only then can I beat Sun Wukong
That's how you get your piece of monk flesh
Now
Do you understand?
Go get changed
Um
What are you waiting for?
If you won't do it I will
Sorry
When
When you came to me
You
You didn't tell me about this
I have always wanted the Tang Monk's flesh
Now we have it
What more do you want?
I've got parents and brothers and sisters
If they can have some monk flesh
What wouldn't I give for that?
Um king
This costume is a bit too big
Put on the mask
Come here
My king you are truly all powerful
Mhmm
Professional after all
Why aren't you changed yet?
What are you waiting for?
Change into costume
Quickly
Stop being so stubborn
Don't you want that Monk flesh?
No way a Yao would turn that down
I
I am not a Yao
I am the Monk
Monkey King
My king
The altar is all set
Ready for inspection my king
Captain Leopard
Throw him in the dungeon
Show him the torture chamber
See if he comes to his senses
Yes king
Take him away
Captain Leopard
Keep rehearsing
Or no monk flesh for anyone
That is one stubborn ape
Let him calm down a bit
Then I'll go talk to him
Let us three
Start practicing while we can
Second Brother
I
You aren't the Sha Monk now
You can talk
What are you doing?
I want to go back
Go back where?
To Lang Lang Mountain
Weren't you in for the monk flesh?
I never said I wanted the monk flesh
When I went out with you guys
You said that fetching the scriptures
can make me a real immortal
Eating the Tang Monk's flesh
also makes you immortal
To get to the Tang Monk
They are going to eat all those children
It feels wrong
There's no right or wrong in this world
Just do what it takes to survive
Side with whoever's more powerful
That's how this world works
Didn't you used to fake your way
to getting food and drink as well?
What's with the high horse?
How are we supposed to pull this off without you?
Hang on
Turn right after those doors
Go through the side gate in the back
No guards there
So that's it then
Why did you let him go?
Are you having doubts yourself?
Stop hesitating
Burn our luggage already
Don't dwell on the past
I'll just grab some Yao to replace the Weasel
You should hurry too
My king
That ape is still reluctant to obey
What do we do with him?
No bloodshed in the temple today
Take him to the back mountain
Yes sir
( Vanquisher of Yaos )
Still no?
Any last words?
I am
The
Mon-
Key
King
This one's gone completely mad
Move forward
Jump down
I heard that loud and clear
You said it yourself this time
You are the Monkey King
I don't know
what kind of act you guys are putting on
What I really don't get is
why you all want me dead
At least I was the second-in-command
back at Dog's Den
Handling you nobodies
Piece of cake
Then try this
Invincible Bulldoze
Is he dead this time?
Should be
Invincible Bulldoze
Hahaha
His head is way harder than yours
Way harder
Watch
What
Out
Let me go
Let him go
Trying to sneak up on me
with that tiny rock?
How about this?
What do we do now?
Can
Can we still go fetch the scriptures?
Stop asking that
That's a dead end
No
We are going to fetch the scriptures
Didn't they say Buddha knows Sun Wukong?
How do we do it then?
This time we're not pretending to be them
We go as ourselves
Why can they fetch the scriptures
But not us?
The full moon rises and the time is nigh
An offering of innocent children
If it pleases the king to bathe and change
The Yellow-Browed's about to eat the kids
What do we do?
If we let all those children die
What's the use of fetching the scriptures?
Where are the children kept?
I
I know
They're kept in the dung
In the dungeon that I was in
That place is crawling with guards
How do we save them?
You used his hair for your beard before
Yeah
This time he is borrowing some of yours
Are the eyebrows holding up?
Yeah
Why is the ape on top?
He knows the way
Then why am I at the bottom?
You are strongest from all that carrying
Turn right
Watch
Watch out for the sta
Sta-
Stairs
My king
The time has come
Send for the children
My king
Are you alright?
Open
Open the doors
Go go go
Arms up-higher
Hey what's wrong with yours?
Can't lift it
Really?
My king
I'm just rehearsing them
Promise everything'll be perfect tomorrow
Alright
Go
Got it
My king
My king you could have just told us
No need for you to come in person
We will deliver them to the altar
My king
That way's the backyard
The altar is up front
My king
You
I
My king
Why are you stuttering?
Insolent
The king will go wherever he pleases
He doesn't need you telling him
Go prep the altar already
Stop following the King around
Right?
My king
Mhmm
Yes
Hey
What about me?
Back to your position
Alright
Come with us
I still want that monk flesh
See you around then
Where are we taking the kids?
The farther the better
Wait until Sun Wukong comes tomorrow
Servants
Here
Attend me
Yes sir
My king
The clothes are gone
Weren't you all tough just now?
Not talking now are we?
My king
Where are the children?
Didn't you take them away yourself?
You've been with me all these years
And you can't even recognize my face?
Who is it
that dares ruin my plan?
Get up quickly
Take him and go
Hurry up
You guys go first
What about you?
Did you forget?
I have my ultimate move
Didn't you say
you could only use it once in your life?
This is that once
Let's go
So it was you
Could've taken the easy way
Hand over the children
You'll have to get through me first
Hahaha
Get through you
And what are you gonna do?
See
I have this ultimate move
I have been practicing it for a long time
But I guess
Fate has it
That today
You will be the one to see it
Ultimate move
What move could you possibly have?
The sky and earth turn
Sun and moon burn
Stars shine in line
Illusions intertwine
Clouds and rains fall
The heart calls
Boys
Get him
You've got quite the hard head
Just you wait
Once Sun Wukong gets here
You're finished
With all the evil you've done
You will be sent to the deepest hell
I'll show you hell first
My king
Just a moment
I'll take care of him for you
The sky and earth turn
Sun and moon burn
Stars shine in line
Illusions intertwine
Clouds and rains fall
The heart calls
Alright
Can you back off a bit?
How do you know this is a fusion move?
I never told you this
Remember that time I was at your place?
Your dad got drunk and told me
Did you know that after using this move
We will go back to our animal forms?
I do
What can I say?
I wanted to be immortal
Now I'm going to be very mortal
Just my luck
Are you two done?
So you've come to help me
Isn't that obvious?
Try to mess with me
Can't touch this
Why do I even bother?
Let's go
There's our chance
Your ultimate move isn't all that great
Now we are finished and we didn't beat him
Are you regretting what you did again?
My biggest regret
was meeting you in the first place
You could have lived a good life
with power like yours
What do you guys even want?
If this move didn't have a time limit
I would've taken you down
Right
A lot of tough talk for a loser
Illusions intertwine
Clouds and rains fall
The heart calls
How do you two know about this?
Know about what?
The fusion move
Your dad told us
When?
That other day at your place
Your dad got drunk and told me
Yeah that
Oh dad
Where are the kids?
All hidden
Hidden where?
I
Won't
Tell
You
Then you guys will die together
Yeah
Hey
That's my foot
Why are you
grabbing it?
Haven't
Haven't washed it in three months
Bring it on
Black Wind Devours the Sun
In Your Face - Literally
This shoddy mace actually hurts
Don't let him notice
Dawn is breaking
You lot ruined my plan
I can't believe
you bunch of nobodies
forced me to use my own ultimate move
You are all beneath me
What's happening?
What?
We are running out of time
Everyone give it everything you've got
Watch out
Toadie
You handle the legs
Got it
I can't hold it much longer
"The Might of a Thousand Mountains"
"None can stand before me"
Boar
Ape
Weasel
Toad punch
I don't get it
What do you want?
I want to
live the life that I want to live
It's just a boy
Time's up
Looks like
we won't be fetching any scriptures in this life
When we all go back to being animals
Think we'll recognize each other?
Hurry up and remember
What we all look like
You
Slightly yellow in the teeth
One eye's bigger than the other
You
Red buttocks
You have red buttocks
I
I'm an ape
Then you have to say Monkey King
See if you stutter
Hahaha
It's not fair
We haven't even done anything in this life
Next life
Let's reincarnate into something better
Hey
I don't even know your names yet
Oh right
My name is
Haha
Kind of cute
Actually
His name is
In the next life
I hope you are someone who talks a lot
Maitreya Buddha
I have sent you here
to be one of the 81 tribulations
that the Tang Monk has to go through
Now look at you
Eating children
I won't dare do it again
Please buddha
Give me another chance
Your powers are weak
You're no match for Wukong
I have just infused you with more power
Take the Golden Cymbal and the Human Seed Bag
Two magical weapons
Be well prepared
Don't mess it up
Thank you buddha
I'll go prepare right away
Your sins this time are unforgivable
I will make note of them
Once the Tang Monk has passed
You will return for your punishment
Yes
Buddha
What about those four?
Wukong
Go check out what lies ahead
Master
It appears to be a temple
Looks like the Thunderclap Temple
But it is giving off dangerous vibes
If there is a Thunderclap
This here is the holy mountain
We have crossed mountains and rivers
to finally arrive here
Go forth quickly
This little piglet is so cute
Looks just like me when I was a kid
( Vanquisher of Yaos )
Brother Monkey
What are you doing?
Heh heh
These little ones
These can save your lives
One for each of you
Come quickly
Brother monkey
Coming
( Three days later )
Brother
Why did it have to be like this?
You were one sip away
If you had
taken that sip like I did
You would be immortal
Just like I am right now
It's a tough world out there
Being a dog ain't easy
Brother
I will find
that fake Sun Wukong
and avenge you